Pimples are caused by the overproduction of sebum oil which lubricates the skin and hair.
I'm Jackie with how to cure pimples with herbs.
When the skin's pores become clogged with sebum, pimples can form.
Talk to your doctor if your acne is serious or you're unable to control it.
There are natural ways to treat pimples and some of them may work for you.
Grind a handful of fresh mint leaves with a few drops of lemon juice and tumeric powder.
Apply this paste to the pimples and let it dry.
Wash with lukewarm water and pat dry.
Tumeric has antibacterial properties to kill germs, and the lemon juice controls the sebum balance of the skin.
Another natural remedy is to make a paste of sandalwood powder and rosewater.
You can find these at your local health food store.
Apply this paste on the affected area and leave it on overnight.
Wash it off in the morning.
Sandalwood lessens irritation and reduces swelling.
Remember, to use herbs to treat pimples, try a paste of fresh mint, lemon juice and tumeric powder, or a paste of sandalwood powder and rosewater.
Check with your doctor for serious cases.
Nobody wants to live with pimples.
I'm Jackie with how to cure pimples with herbs.
Have a great day.